volumio.org 2019-06-14

# Privacy Policy of Volumio · Volumio

Volumio collects some Personal Data from its Users.

Users may be subject to different protection standards and broader standards may therefore apply to some. In order to learn more about the protection criteria, Users can refer to the applicability section.

## Owner and Data Controller

INTUITU di Michelangelo Guarise -Via de Pepi 76r – 50122 Firenze (Italy)

**Owner contact email:** info@volumio.org

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that Volumio collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies; Usage Data; unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example); email address; password; first name; last name; picture; username; social media accounts ; address; company name; country; province; ZIP/Postal code; city; billing address; shipping address; prefix . 

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.

Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using Volumio.

Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by Volumio is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for Volumio to provide its services. In cases where Volumio specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.

Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.

Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by Volumio or by the owners of third-party services used by Volumio serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through Volumio and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Methods of processing

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.

The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of Volumio (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.

### Legal basis of processing

The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:

  * Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes. Note: Under some legislations the Owner may be allowed to process Personal Data until the User objects to such processing (“opt-out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the following legal bases. This, however, does not apply, whenever the processing of Personal Data is subject to European data protection law;
  * provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;
  * processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;
  * processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;
  * processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.

In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract. 

### Place

The Data is processed at the Owner’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.

Depending on the User’s location, data transfers may involve transferring the User’s Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

If broader protection standards are applicable, Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of Data transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.

If any such transfer takes place, Users can find out more by checking the relevant sections of this document or inquire with the Owner using the information provided in the contact section.

### Retention time

Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for.

Therefore:

  * Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.
  * Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.

Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

## The purposes of processing

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Services, as well as for the following purposes: Access to third party accounts, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Advertising, Remarketing and behavioral targeting, Commercial affiliation, SPAM protection, Analytics, Handling payments, Hosting and backend infrastructure, Registration and authentication, Traffic optimization and distribution, Content commenting, Managing contacts and sending messages, Infrastructure monitoring, Social features, Content performance and features testing (A/B testing), Displaying content from external platforms, Contacting the User and Platform services and hosting. 

Users can find further detailed information about such purposes of processing and about the specific Personal Data used for each purpose in the respective sections of this document.

## Facebook permissions asked by Volumio

Volumio may ask for some Facebook permissions allowing it to perform actions with the User’s Facebook account and to retrieve information, including Personal Data, from it. This service allows Volumio to connect with the User’s account on the Facebook social network, provided by Facebook Inc.

For more information about the following permissions, refer to the [Facebook permissions documentation](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/authentication/permissions/) and to the [Facebook privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

The permissions asked are the following:

### Basic information

By default, this includes certain User’s Data such as id, name, picture, gender, and their locale. Certain connections of the User, such as the Friends, are also available. If the User has made more of their Data public, more information will be available.

### Access private data

Access the User’s and friends’ private data.

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

### Access to third party accounts

This type of service allows Volumio to access Data from your account on a third party service and perform actions with it.

These services are not activated automatically, but require explicit authorization by the User.

#### Facebook account access (Volumio)

This service allows Volumio to connect with the User’s account on the Facebook social network, provided by Facebook, Inc.

Permissions asked: Access private data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php). 

#### Twitter account access (Twitter, Inc.)

This service allows Volumio to connect with the User’s account on the Twitter social network, provided by Twitter, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy). 

### Advertising

This type of service allows User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on Volumio, possibly based on User interests.

This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.

Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside Volumio. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.

In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

#### AdMob (AdMob Google Inc.)

AdMob is an advertising service provided by AdMob Google Inc.

**In order to understand Google’s use of Data, consult[Google’s partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)**.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example); Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). 

#### Google Ad Manager (Google Inc.)

Google Ad Manager is an advertising service provided by Google LLC that allows the Owner to run advertising campaigns in conjunction with external advertising networks that the Owner, unless otherwise specified in this document, has no direct relationship with. In order to opt out from being tracked by various advertising networks, Users may make use of [Youronlinechoices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/). In order to understand Google’s use of data, consult [Google’s partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

This service uses the “DoubleClick” Cookie, which tracks use of Volumio and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.   Users may decide to disable all the DoubleClick Cookies by clicking on: [www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en).

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Google AdSense (Google Inc.)

Google AdSense is an advertising service provided by Google Inc. This service uses the “Doubleclick” Cookie, which tracks use of Volumio and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.

Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies by clicking on: [google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout).

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout). 

#### Outbrain (Outbrain Inc.)

Outbrain is an advertising service provided by Outbrain Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy#advertising_behavioral_targeting). 

### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Alexa Metrics (Alexa Internet, Inc.)

Alexa Metrics is an analytics service provided by Alexa Internet, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.alexa.com/help/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.alexa.com/settings/optout). 

#### Display Advertising extension for Google Analytics (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics on Volumio might use Google’s Interest-based advertising, 3rd-party audience data and information from the DoubleClick Cookie to extend analytics with demographics, interests and ads interaction data.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

#### User ID extension for Google Analytics (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics on Volumio makes use of a feature called User ID. This setup allows for a more accurate tracking of Users by associating that User with the same ID over various sessions and devices. It is set up in a way that doesn’t allow Google to personally identify an individual or permanently identify a particular device.

The User ID extension might make it possible to connect Data from Google Analytics with other Data about the User collected by Volumio.

The opt-out link below will only opt you out for the device you are on, but not from tracking performed independently by the Owner. Contact the Owner via the email address provided in this privacy policy to object to the aforementioned tracking as well.

Personal Data collected: Cookies. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Google Analytics (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of Volumio, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.

Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). 

#### Google Analytics with anonymized IP (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of Volumio, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.

Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

This integration of Google Analytics anonymizes your IP address. It works by shortening Users’ IP addresses within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP address be sent to a Google server and shortened within the US.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). 

#### Google Analytics for Firebase (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics for Firebase or Firebase Analytics is an analytics service provided by Google Inc.

**In order to understand Google’s use of Data, consult[Google’s partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)**.

Firebase Analytics may share Data with other tools provided by Firebase, such as Crash Reporting, Authentication, Remote Config or Notifications. The User may check this privacy policy to find a detailed explanation about the other tools used by the Owner.

Volumio uses identifiers for mobile devices and technologies similar to cookies to run the Firebase Analytics service.

Users may opt-out of certain Firebase features through applicable device settings, such as the device advertising settings for mobile phones or by following the instructions in other Firebase related sections of this privacy policy, if available.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example); Usage Data. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### WordPress Stats (Automattic Inc.)

WordPress Stats is an analytics service provided by Automattic Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/). 

#### Quantcast Measure (Quantcast Corporation)

Quantcast Measure is an analytics service provided by Quantcast Corporation.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.quantcast.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.quantcast.com/opt-out). 

#### Google Ads conversion tracking (Google Inc.)

Google Ads conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google Inc. that connects data from the Google Ads advertising network with actions performed on Volumio.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. 

### Commercial affiliation

This type of service allows Volumio to display advertisements for third party products or services. Ads can be displayed either as advertising links or as banners using various kinds of graphics.

Clicks on the icon or banner posted on the Application are tracked by the third-party services listed below, and are shared with Volumio.

For details of which data are collected, please refer to the privacy policy of each service.

#### Affilinet (Affilinet GmbH)

Affilinet is a banner commercial affiliation service provided by Affilinet GmbH.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: Germany – [Privacy Policy](https://www.affili.net/uk/footeritem/privacy-policy). 

#### Amazon Affiliation (Amazon)

Amazon Affiliation is a commercial affiliation service provided by Amazon.com Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=hp_rel_topic?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496). 

#### eBay Partner Network (eBay, Inc.)

eBay Partner Network è un servizio di affiliazione commerciale fornito da eBay, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://partnernetwork.ebay.co.uk/legal#privacy-policy). 

### Contacting the User

#### Mailing list or newsletter (Volumio)

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning Volumio. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to Volumio or after making a purchase.

Personal Data collected: email address; first name. 

#### Contact form (Volumio)

By filling in the contact form with their Data, the User authorizes Volumio to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.

Personal Data collected: email address; first name. 

#### SumoMe Mailing List or Newsletter (Sumo Group Inc.)

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning Volumio. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to Volumio or after making a purchase.

Personal Data collected: email address; first name; last name. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.appsumo.com/privacy/). 

### Content commenting

Content commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of Volumio.

Depending on the settings chosen by the Owner, Users may also leave anonymous comments. If there is an email address among the Personal Data provided by the User, it may be used to send notifications of comments on the same content. Users are responsible for the content of their own comments.

If a content commenting service provided by third parties is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the comment service is installed, even when Users do not use the content commenting service.

#### Disqus (Disqus)

Disqus is a content commenting service provided by Big Heads Labs Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/466259-privacy-policy) – [Opt out](https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/1657951). 

#### Facebook Comments (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Comments is a content commenting service provided by Facebook, Inc. enabling the User to leave comments and share them on the Facebook platform.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation). 

### Content performance and features testing (A/B testing)

The services contained in this section allow the Owner to track and analyze the User response concerning web traffic or behavior regarding changes to the structure, text or any other component of Volumio.

#### Firebase Remote Config (Google Inc.)

Firebase Remote Config is an A/B testing and configuration service provided by Google Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Google Website Optimizer (Google Inc.)

Google Website Optimizer is an A/B testing service provided by Google Inc.

Google may use Personal Data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/policies/privacy/). 

### Displaying content from external platforms

This type of service allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of Volumio and interact with them.

This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### Google Site Search (Google Inc.)

Google Site Search is a search engine embedding service provided by Google Inc. that allows Volumio to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). 

#### Gravatar (Automattic Inc.)

Gravatar is an image visualization service provided by Automattic Inc. that allows Volumio to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Please note that if Gravatar images are used for comment forms, the commenter’s email address or parts of it may be sent to Gravatar – even if the commenter has not signed up for that service.

Personal Data collected: email address; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/). 

#### GitHub button and social widgets (GitHub Inc.)

The GitHub button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the GitHub and Gist services provided by GitHub, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://help.github.com/articles/github-privacy-statement/). Privacy Shield participant. 

### Handling payments

Payment processing services enable Volumio to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, Volumio shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction.

Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.

#### Amazon Payments (Amazon)

Amazon Payments is a payment service provided by Amazon.com, Inc., which allows Users to make online payments using their Amazon credentials.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: See the Amazon privacy policy – [Privacy Policy](https://payments.amazon.com/help/Personal-Accounts/Privacy-Security/Privacy-Notice). 

#### Balanced Payments (Balanced)

Balanced Payments is a payment service provided by Balanced Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.balancedpayments.com/privacy). 

#### Coinbase (Coinbase Inc.)

Coinbase is a payment service provided by Coinbase, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.coinbase.com/legal/privacy). 

### Hosting and backend infrastructure

This type of service has the purpose of hosting data and files that enable Volumio to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of Volumio. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.

#### Amazon Web Services (AWS) (Amazon)

Amazon Web Services is a hosting and backend service provided by Amazon.com Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: See the Amazon privacy policy – [Privacy Policy](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/). 

#### DigitalOcean (DigitalOcean Inc.)

DigitalOcean is a hosting service provided by DigitalOcean Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.digitalocean.com/legal/privacy/). 

#### Firebase Cloud Firestore (Google Inc.)

Firebase Cloud Firestore is a hosting and backend service provided by Google Inc.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://firebase.google.com/). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Firebase Cloud Functions (Google Inc.)

Firebase Cloud Functions is a hosting and backend service provided by Google Inc.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Firebase Cloud Storage (Google Inc.)

Firebase Cloud Storage is a hosting service provided by Google Inc.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Firebase Hosting (Firebase, Inc.)

Firebase Hosting is a hosting service provided by Firebase, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Firebase Realtime Database (Google Inc.)

Firebase Realtime Database is a hosting and backend service provided by Google Inc.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Google App Engine (Google Inc.)

Google App Engine is a hosting service provided by Google Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### MyVolumio 

Goal of MyVolumio

Provide an enhanced experience with Volumio, by allowing control of several Volumio devices from a single dashboard

Provide an infrastructure to easily expand compatibility with third party music services

Adding over time several new capabilities, thanks to the extra funding received

Data Collection and usage

Due to the nature of the services and the features that we offer, we store (in a very secure manner) some of your data, specifically:

Name, surname, email and geographical location

Favourites, Playlists, Radio Favourites, Personal Radios and the last played song on each device

Date and time of your first subscription

Data pertaining to your devices: anonimized Unique Identifier, Hardware type, Friendly name, System version and date of first addition

What is your data used for:

Matching the nearest server to your location to enhance your experience with the lowest possible latency

Synchronize in real time Favourites, Playlists, Radio Favourites, Personal Radios

Verify that you have an active subscription

Offering a clear overview of how many devices are linked to your account and if they are currently available and what they are currently playing

General Policy of User Data

By cancelling your account, your data will be permanently deleted instantly

We will not sell, share or grant access to your data to anyone.

You will be able to download a file containing all your aforementioned data (except those that might result in a security issue)

#### GitHub Pages (GitHub Inc.)

GitHub Pages is a hosting service provided by GitHub, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://help.github.com/articles/github-privacy-statement/). Privacy Shield participant. 

### Infrastructure monitoring

This type of service allows Volumio to monitor the use and behavior of its components so its performance, operation, maintenance and troubleshooting can be improved.

Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and mode of implementation of these services, whose function is to filter the activities of Volumio.

#### Firebase Crash Reporting (Google Inc.)

Firebase Crash Reporting is a monitoring service provided by Google, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). 

#### Firebase Performance Monitoring (Google Ireland Limited)

Firebase Performance Monitoring is a monitoring service provided by Google Ireland Limited.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy). Privacy Shield participant. 

### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of Volumio.

The interaction and information obtained through Volumio are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.

This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### AddThis (Addthis Inc.)

AddThis is a service provided by Clearspring Technologies Inc., which displays a widget that allows interaction with social networks and external platforms as well as sharing the contents of Volumio.

Depending on the configuration, this service can display widgets belonging to third parties such as the managers of social networks where interactions are shared. In this case, also the third parties that provide the widget will be informed of interactions and Usage Data on the pages where this service is installed.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy). 

#### Buffer button and social widgets (Buffer)

The Buffer button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Buffer service provided by Buffer, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://bufferapp.com/privacy). 

#### PayPal button and widgets (PayPal Inc.)

The PayPal button and widgets are services allowing interaction with the PayPal platform provided by PayPal Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: See the PayPal privacy policy – [Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=p/gen/ua/policy_privacy-outside). 

### Managing contacts and sending messages

This type of service makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.

These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

#### Firebase Cloud Messaging (Google Inc.)

Firebase Cloud Messaging is a message sending service provided by Google, Inc. Firebase Cloud Messaging allows the Owner to send messages and notifications to Users across platforms such as Android, iOS, and the web. Messages can be sent to single devices, groups of devices, or specific topics or User segments.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). 

#### Mailchimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC.)

Mailchimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC.

Personal Data collected: email address. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Mailgun (Mailgun, Inc.)

Mailgun is an email address management and message sending service provided by Mailgun, Inc.

Personal Data collected: email address. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.mailgun.com/privacy). 

#### Firebase Notifications (Google Ireland Limited)

Firebase Notifications is a message sending service provided by Google Ireland Limited. Firebase Notifications can be integrated with Firebase Analytics to target analytics-based audiences and track opening and conversion events.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy). Privacy Shield participant. 

### Platform services and hosting

These services have the purpose of hosting and running key components of Volumio, therefore allowing the provision of Volumio from within a unified platform. Such platforms provide a wide range of tools to the Owner – e.g. analytics, user registration, commenting, database management, e-commerce, payment processing – that imply the collection and handling of Personal Data. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.

#### WordPress.com (Automattic Inc.)

WordPress.com is a platform provided by Automattic Inc. that allows the Owner to build, run and host Volumio.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/). 

### Registration and authentication

By registering or authenticating, Users allow Volumio to identify them and give them access to dedicated services.

Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, Volumio will be able to access some Data, stored by these third party services, for registration or identification purposes.

#### Auth0 (Auth0, Inc)

Auth0 is a registration and authentication service provided by Auth0, Inc. To simplify the registration and authentication process, Auth0 can make use of third party identity providers and save the information on its platform.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; email address; first name; last name; password; picture; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://auth0.com/privacy). 

#### Facebook Authentication (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Authentication is a registration and authentication service provided by Facebook, Inc. and is connected to the Facebook social network.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/help/405977429438260). 

#### Firebase Authentication (Google Inc.)

Firebase Authentication is a registration and authentication service provided by Google Inc. To simplify the registration and authentication process, Firebase Authentication can make use of third party identity providers and save the information on its platform.

Personal Data collected: email address; first name; last name; password; social media accounts ; username. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). 

#### Google OAuth (Google Inc.)

Google OAuth is a registration and authentication service provided by Google Inc. and is connected to the Google network.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). 

#### Direct registration (Volumio)

The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to Volumio.

Personal Data collected: address; billing address; city; company name; country; email address; last name; password; prefix ; province; shipping address; username; ZIP/Postal code. 

#### GitHub OAuth (GitHub Inc.)

GitHub OAuth is a registration and authentication service provided by GitHub Inc. and is connected to the GitHub network.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://help.github.com/articles/github-privacy-statement/). Privacy Shield participant. 

### Remarketing and behavioral targeting

This type of service allows Volumio and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of Volumio by the User.

This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.

In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

#### AdWords Remarketing (Google Inc.)

AdWords Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the activity of Volumio with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout). 

#### Google Ad Manager Audience Extension (Google Inc.)

Google Ad Manager Audience Extension is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google Inc. that tracks the visitors of Volumio and allows selected advertising partners to display targeted ads across the web to them.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb#display_optout). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Facebook Remarketing (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects the activity of Volumio with the Facebook advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/). 

### Social features

#### Firebase Dynamic Links (Google Inc.)

Firebase Dynamic Links is a social feature provided by Google Inc. Dynamic Links are tracked within Firebase or Google Analytics for Firebase, which informs the Owner about the details of the User journey to and within Volumio.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Firebase Invites (Google Inc.)

Firebase Invites is a social feature provided by Google Inc. that enables Users to share Volumio. The sharing may contain referral codes, or content from within Volumio and may be done via email or SMS. Sharing is tracked with Google Analytics for Firebase, which informs the Owner that the User has opened or installed Volumio via invite.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant. 

### SPAM protection

This type of service analyzes the traffic of Volumio, potentially containing Users’ Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as SPAM.

#### Akismet (Automattic Inc.)

Akismet is a SPAM protection service provided by Automattic Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/). 

### Traffic optimization and distribution

This type of service allows Volumio to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance.

Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented. Their function is to filter communications between Volumio and the User’s browser.

Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information User are transferred.

#### Cloudflare (Cloudflare)

Cloudflare is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by Cloudflare Inc.

The way Cloudflare is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through Volumio, i.e., communication between Volumio and the User’s browser, while also allowing analytical data from Volumio to be collected.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy/). 

## The rights of Users

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

Users entitled to broader protection standards may exercise any of the rights described below. In all other cases, Users may inquire with the Owner to find out which rights apply to them.

In particular, Users have the right to do the following:

  * **Withdraw their consent at any time.** Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
  * **Object to processing of their Data.** Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided in the dedicated section below.
  * **Access their Data.** Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
  * **Verify and seek rectification.** Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
  * **Restrict the processing of their Data.** Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it. 
  * **Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed.** Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.
  * **Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller.** Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is based on the User’s consent, on a contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations thereof.
  * **Lodge a complaint.** Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.

### Details about the right to object to processing

Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.

Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document. 

### How to exercise these rights

Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month.

## Applicability of broader protection standards

While most provisions of this document concern all Users, some provisions expressly only apply if the processing of Personal Data is subject to broader protection standards.

Such broader protection standards apply when the processing:

  * is performed by an Owner based within the EU;
  * concerns the Personal Data of Users who are in the EU and is related to the offering of paid or unpaid goods or services, to such Users;
  * concerns the Personal Data of Users who are in the EU and allows the Owner to monitor such Users’ behavior taking place in the EU.

## Cookie Policy

Volumio uses Cookies. To learn more and for a detailed cookie notice, the User may consult the Cookie Policy.

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

### Legal action

The User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of Volumio or the related Services.

The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities. 

### Additional information about User’s Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, Volumio may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request. 

### System logs and maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, Volumio and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with Volumio (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose. 

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document. 

### How “Do Not Track” requests are handled

Volumio does not support “Do Not Track” requests.

To determine whether any of the third-party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies. 

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page and possibly within Volumio and/or – as far as technically and legally feasible – sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom.

Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the User, where required. 

###  Definitions and legal references 

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically through Volumio (or third-party services employed in Volumio), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use Volumio, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User’s IT environment.

#### User

The individual using Volumio who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.

#### Data Subject

The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of Volumio. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of Volumio.

####  Volumio (or this Application) 

The means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.

#### Service

The service provided by Volumio as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this site/application.

#### European Union (or EU) 

Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area. 

#### Cookies

Small piece of data stored in the User’s device.

#### Legal information

This privacy statement has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations, including Art. 13/14 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation).

This privacy policy relates solely to Volumio, if not stated otherwise within this document.

Latest update: March 25, 2019
